<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>news on Institute of Infomation Systems at HU-Berlin</title>
    <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in news on Institute of Infomation Systems at HU-Berlin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 11:46:06 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Job Positions</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/jobs/</guid>
      <description>Februar 2018  KPMG sucht Absolventen als Werkstudenten/Praktikanten (m/w), CIO Advisory - IT-Strategie
Mehr Infos hier
 ICT Graduate Programme - Apply online on hier
 MOIA - Social Movement bietet eine Werkstudentenstelle im Bereich IT-Infrastructure, mehr Infos hier!
 Das Innovationszentrum Connected Living e.V. veranstaltet unter dem Titel „With Data Analytics to new Connected Home Energy Concepts“ vom 9.-11. März 2018 bei SAP in Berlin gemeinsam mit seinen Partnern SAP, Vattenfall, innogy, Conrad, TU Berlin (DAI-Labor), Fresh Energy, Signal Cruncher und IOLITE seinen ersten Hackathon „ConnHack 2018 - Shape The Future Of Connected Life”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Night Series: final session for Winter Term</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/bcn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/bcn/</guid>
      <description>Final Blockchain Night of Winter semester is coming up soon!
ICOs ever overcome the currently shady public image? Will they leave venture funds out of business and open a new era of crowdfunding? Our speakers have first-hand ICO expertise and will offer their unique views on this controversial subject.
 Dr Philipp Hacker from HU Law School will start the discussion exploring the current legal framework of EU followed by Ingmar Wegel, vice president at Clipperton (international M&amp;amp;A advisors) who will share the current industry experience on raising funds through ICOs and why it might not be a good idea concluded by Balazs Deme, CEO at Herdius - first startup to boldly launch an ICO in Germany  Wether or not you are planning to participate or launch an ICO in the nearest future, we invite you to register at www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consultation Hours</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/consultationhours/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/consultationhours/</guid>
      <description>As of 19th October 2017 (WS 2017 / 18) consultation hours with Prof. Lessmann will take place as follows:
all students on Thursday 10 - 11 am. Because of the great demand, appointments will be given only with previous registration by sending an e-mail to bujarek@hu-berlin.de.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open three year PhD Position</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/phdposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/phdposition/</guid>
      <description>We seek applications for a three year PhD position (0.75 E13) in Bereich Credit Risk Analytics. Please send your application by email to Prof. Lessmann.(Deadline: 09.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Courses for Summer Term 2018 online</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/newcourseoutline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/newcourseoutline/</guid>
      <description>Shortly you can find the courses for the upcoming summer term 2018 here!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>