<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>news on Institute of Infomation Systems at HU-Berlin</title>
    <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in news on Institute of Infomation Systems at HU-Berlin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 11:46:06 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Courses for Summer Term 2019 online</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/newcourseoutline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/newcourseoutline/</guid>
      <description>Advanced Data Analytics for Management Support The module Advanced Data Analytics for Management Support (ADAMS) introduces students to the latest developments in the scope of data-driven management support. It covers relevant theories and concepts in machine learning against the background of concrete real-world applications in management science. Special emphasize is given to the analysis of textual data and other complex data such as sequences or images. Corresponding data is typically approached using the framework of deep artificial neural networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Job Positions</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/jobs/</guid>
      <description>März 2019  Momentan gibt es keine neuen Jobangebote Currently, there are no jobs available </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> PhD Position</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/phdposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/phdposition/</guid>
      <description>Currently no open positions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consultation Hours</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/consultationhours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/consultationhours/</guid>
      <description>As of March 2019 (SS 2019) consultation hours with Prof. Lessmann will take place as follows:
all students on Thursday 10 - 11 am. Because of the great demand, appointments will be given only with previous registration by sending an e-mail to bujarek@hu-berlin.de.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Night Series: final session for Winter Term</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/bcn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/bcn/</guid>
      <description>Final Blockchain Night of Winter semester is coming up soon!
ICOs ever overcome the currently shady public image? Will they leave venture funds out of business and open a new era of crowdfunding? Our speakers have first-hand ICO expertise and will offer their unique views on this controversial subject.
 Dr Philipp Hacker from HU Law School will start the discussion exploring the current legal framework of EU followed by Ingmar Wegel, vice president at Clipperton (international M&amp;amp;A advisors) who will share the current industry experience on raising funds through ICOs and why it might not be a good idea concluded by Balazs Deme, CEO at Herdius - first startup to boldly launch an ICO in Germany  Wether or not you are planning to participate or launch an ICO in the nearest future, we invite you to register at www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>