<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Members on Institute of Infomation Systems at HU-Berlin</title>
    <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Members on Institute of Infomation Systems at HU-Berlin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, Chair of Information System at HU-Berlin; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prof. Dr. Stefan Lessmann</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/lessmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/lessmann/</guid>
      <description>Short-bio Stefan received a diploma in business administration and a PhD from the University of Hamburg in 2002 and 2007, respectively. Stefan worked as a lecturer and senior lecture in business informatics at the Institute of Information Systems of the University of Hamburg. Since 2008, Stefan is a guest lecturer at the School of Management of University of Southampton, where he teaches under- and postgraduate courses on quantitative methods, electronic business, and web application development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johannes Haupt, M.Sc.</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/haupt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/haupt/</guid>
      <description>Short-bio Since April 2016, he has been working as a researcher at the Chair of Information Systems of the Business and Economics department. He implemented a machine learning framework to detect tracking objects in e-mails as part of his master&amp;rsquo;s thesis. In the course of his PhD, he researches applications for machine learning in e-commerce and unstructured data

Research Interests  Customer behavior in e-Commerce
 Recommendation Engines</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annika Baumann, M.Sc.</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/baumann/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/baumann/</guid>
      <description>Short-bio Annika Baumann, M.Sc., studied the Master in Information Systems at the Humboldt University in Berlin. Since June 2013 she works as a researcher at the Institute of information systems at the Humboldt University in Berlin. As part of her master&amp;rsquo;s thesis she investigated the robustness of the Internet graph based on a current dataset. In the course of her PhD she investigates the Internet topology, the readability of privacy policies as well as the social news aggregator Reddit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class of 2017 / 2018 </title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/class1718/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/class1718/</guid>
      <description>The students of the Seminar Information Systems contributed to this website to great extend. Groups of Master students from Humboldt University with backgrounds in Business, Economics, Statistics or Computer Science worked on analytical topics and created blog posts, presenting exciting insights into the following topis:
 Neural Networks and Convolutional Neural Networks Image Analysis Text Mining Time Series Analysis with LSTMs Survial Analysis Image Captioning Deep Learning and Recommender Systems  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>