<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Text Classification on Institute of Infomation Systems at HU-Berlin</title>
    <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/tags/text-classification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Text Classification on Institute of Infomation Systems at HU-Berlin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/tags/text-classification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Synthetic Comments to Balance Data for Text Classification</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/information_systems_1920/text_generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/information_systems_1920/text_generation/</guid>
      <description>LatexIT.add(&#39;p&#39;,true);   Table of Contents  Introduction Data Exploration Data Pre-Processing Text Generation(1): Language Model - GloVe  Further Text Preparation Modeling Generation   Text Generation(2): Language Model - GPT-2  Why GPT-2? What makes GPT-2 so powerful? The Problem of Long-Term Dependencies GPT-2 Architecture How does GPT-2 create text? Input Encoding 1. Token Embeddings (wte) 2. Positional Encoding (wpe) GPT-2 - Token Processing Overview Self-Attention Process 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Peer Review Challenge</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/information_systems_1920/group11_peer_reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/information_systems_1920/group11_peer_reviews/</guid>
      <description>Big Peer Review Challenge Asena Ciloglu &amp;amp; Melike Merdan Abstract This blog post studies the first public dataset of scientific peer reviews available for research purposes PeerRead applying state-of-the-art NLP models ELMo and ULMFit to a text classification task [1]. It aims to examine the importance of the peer reviews on paper’s acceptance or rejection decision in well-known conferences of computational linguistics, AI and NLP.
Table of Contents   Introduction  Peer Review Process Motivation    Descriptive Analytics  A Dataset of Peer Reviews  Approach and Data Extraction   Google Scholarly Data Cleaning Data &amp;amp; Insights    Application  Our Approach  Content-based Classification Review-based Classification Analysis with Auxiliary Data   Transfer Learning and Recent Applications Embedding for Language Models (ELMo)  Methodology  Deep Contextualized Word Representations Model Architecture     Universal Language Model Fine Tuning (ULMFit)  Methodology  General Knowledge Domain Training Target Task Language Model Fine Tuning Target Task Classifier     Support Vector Machine (SVM)    Empirical Results &amp;amp; Conclusion  Results Discussion and Conclusion    Reference List  1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>