<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Institute of Infomation Systems at HU-Berlin</title>
    <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Institute of Infomation Systems at HU-Berlin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prof. Dr. Stefan Lessmann</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/lessmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/lessmann/</guid>
      <description>Short-bio Stefan received a diploma in business administration and a PhD from the University of Hamburg in 2002 and 2007, respectively. Stefan worked as a lecturer and senior lecture in business informatics at the Institute of Information Systems of the University of Hamburg. Since 2008, Stefan is a guest lecturer at the School of Management of University of Southampton, where he teaches under- and postgraduate courses on quantitative methods, electronic business, and web application development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johannes Haupt, M.Sc.</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/haupt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/haupt/</guid>
      <description>Short-bio Since April 2016, he has been working as a researcher at the Chair of Information Systems of the Business and Economics department. He implemented a machine learning framework to detect tracking objects in e-mails as part of his master&amp;rsquo;s thesis. In the course of his PhD, he researches applications for machine learning in e-commerce and unstructured data

Research Interests  Customer behavior in e-Commerce
 Recommendation Engines</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annika Baumann, M.Sc.</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/baumann/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/baumann/</guid>
      <description>Short-bio Annika Baumann, M.Sc., studied the Master in Information Systems at the Humboldt University in Berlin. Since June 2013 she works as a researcher at the Institute of information systems at the Humboldt University in Berlin. As part of her master&amp;rsquo;s thesis she investigated the robustness of the Internet graph based on a current dataset. In the course of her PhD she investigates the Internet topology, the readability of privacy policies as well as the social news aggregator Reddit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class of 2017 / 2018 </title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/class1718/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/member/class1718/</guid>
      <description>The students of the Seminar Information Systems contributed to this website to great extend. Groups of Master students from Humboldt University with backgrounds in Business, Economics, Statistics or Computer Science worked on analytical topics and created blog posts, presenting exciting insights into the following topis:
 Neural Networks and Convolutional Neural Networks Image Analysis Text Mining Time Series Analysis with LSTMs Survial Analysis Image Captioning Deep Learning and Recommender Systems  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uplift Modelling</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/uplift_modeling_blogpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/uplift_modeling_blogpost/</guid>
      <description>Uplift Modeling Blogcode{white-space: pre;}pre:not([class]) {background-color: white;}if (window.hljs) {hljs.configure({languages: []});hljs.initHighlightingOnLoad();if (document.readyState &amp;&amp; document.readyState === &#34;complete&#34;) {window.setTimeout(function() { hljs.initHighlighting(); }, 0);}}h1 {font-size: 34px;}h1.title {font-size: 38px;}h2 {font-size: 30px;}h3 {font-size: 24px;}h4 {font-size: 18px;}h5 {font-size: 16px;}h6 {font-size: 12px;}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN)</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/02convolutionalneuralnetworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/02convolutionalneuralnetworks/</guid>
      <description>Convolutional Neural Networks Authors: Elias Baumann, Franko Maximilian Hölzig, Josef Lorenz Rumberger Table of Content  Motivation Images Artificial Neural Networks Convolutional Neural Networks  Architecture Overview Layers Convolutional Layer  Filters Convolution for Functions Mathematical 2D convolution Back to 2D convolution Stride Padding Local receptive fields Parameter Sharing Weight Initialization im2col Convolution using im2col  Activation Function Layer  Why is a non-linear function needed? Logistic sigmoid function hyperbolic tangent function Rectified Linear Units  Pooling Layer  Max Pooling Average Pooling  Fully-connected Layer Forward pass in a convolutional neural network using im2col  The backpropagation algorithm  Backpropagation for Pooling layers The gradient descent algorithm The Vanishing Gradient Problem  Optimizing gradient descent  Stochastic gradient descent Mini-batch gradient descent Learning Rate  Transfer Learning Other interesting use cases for CNNs  Videos Neural language processing Variant calling   Motivation Within the last few years we observed a large increase of visual data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial Time Series Predicting with Long Short-Term Memory</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/06financialtime-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/06financialtime-series/</guid>
      <description>Financial Time Series Predicting with Long Short-Term Memory Authors: Daniel Binsfeld, David Alexander Fradin, Malte Leuschner Introduction Failing to forecast the weather can get us wet in the rain, failing to predict stock prices can cause a loss of money and so can an incorrect prediction of a patient’s medical condition lead to health impairments or to decease. However, relying on multiple information sources, using powerful machines and complex algorithms brought us to a point where the prediction error is as little as it has ever been before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Analysis: Introduction to deep learning for computer vision</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/03imageanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/03imageanalysis/</guid>
      <description>Image Analysis: Introduction to deep learning for computer vision Authors: Nargiz Bakhshaliyeva, Severin Hußmann, Robert Kittel In this blog, we present the practical use of deep learning in computer vision. You will see how Convolutional Neural Networks are being applied to process the visual data, generating some valuable knowledge. In particular, we focused on the object recognition task, aiming to classify what kind of an object (a dog or a cat) is presented within a particular image by using the notion of Transfer Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numeric representation of text documents: doc2vec how it works and how you implement it</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/04topicmodels/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/04topicmodels/</guid>
      <description>Numeric representation of text documents: doc2vec how it works and how you implement it Authors: Felix Idelberger, Alisa Kolesnikova, Jonathan Mühlenpfordt Introduction Natural language processing (NLP) received a lot of attention from academia and industry over the recent decade, benefiting from the introduction of new algorithms for processing the vast corpora of digitized text. A set of language modeling and feature learning techniques called word embeddings became increasingly popular for NLP tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Mining - Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/05sentimentanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/05sentimentanalysis/</guid>
      <description>Sentiment Analysis using Deep Learning Authors: Katja Metzger, Aydin Sader Fosalaie, Ninos Yonan Outline  Sentiment Analysis Introduction  Case Study  Keras IMDB Dataset
 Data Analysis
 Word Embeddings
 Convolutional Neural Network
  Summary  Sentiment Analysis Introduction Sentiment analysis is a very beneficial approach to automate the classification of the polarity of a given text. A helpful indication to decide if the customers on amazon like a product or not is for example the star rating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wide and Deep Learning Model for Grocery Product Recommendations</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/08recommendation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/08recommendation/</guid>
      <description>Recommendation Systems Authors: Jingyi Liu, Brijesh Nanavati, Bharathi Srinivasan 
Introduction The explosion of information with the advent of the Internet and the multitude of choices available to customers introduces complexity in a customer’s decision processes. Recommender system is a useful information-filtering tool, which guides customers to a narrower selection of products and consequently helps them make better decisions. Matching users to the right products saves customers time and effort leading to increased user satisfaction, which in turn earns customer loyalty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Manual on How To Write a Blog Post</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/instruction/manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/instruction/manual/</guid>
      <description>The Website of the Institute of Information Systems is based on a framework called Hugo. Hugo is a static website generator, which allows us to easily present your content of your deep learning projects. In order to present results in the best way, we combine this tool with another tool called Gist. Within this documentation you will learn how to work with those tools. The manual is composed of following sections:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Captioning</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/07imagecaptioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/07imagecaptioning/</guid>
      <description>Image Captioning Authors: Benjamin Jaidi, Simon Remy, Murat Gökhan Yigit Introduction Image captioning aims for automatically generating a text that describes the present picture. In the last years it became a topic with growing interest in machine learning and the advances in this field lead to models that (depending on which evaluation) can score even higher than humans do. Image captioning can for instance help visually impaired people to grasp what is happening in a picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Job Positions</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/jobs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Night Series: final session for Winter Term</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/bcn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/bcn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consultation Hours</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/consultationhours/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/consultationhours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open three year PhD Position</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/phdposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/phdposition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Courses for Summer Term 2018 online</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/newcourseoutline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/news/newcourseoutline/</guid>
      <description>Shortly you can find the courses for the upcoming summer term 2018 here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Network Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/01neuralnetworkfundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/01neuralnetworkfundamentals/</guid>
      <description>Neural Network Fundamentals Authors: Mahdi Bayat, Denis Augusto Pinto Maciel, Roman Proskalovich This blog post is a guide to help readers build a neural network from the very basics. It starts with an introduction to the concept of a neural networks concept and its early development. A step-by-step coding tutorial follows, through which relevant concepts are illustrated. Later in the post, there is also an introduction on how to build neural networks in Keras.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks into Production</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/09deeplearningintoproduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/seminar/09deeplearningintoproduction/</guid>
      <description>Neural Networks into Production Authors: Mahdi Bayat, Denis Augusto Pinto Maciel, Roman Proskalovich Motivation Training and tuning machine learning model is a hard task. There are many variables involved that can make or break your results. However, also very important is, after fine tuning your model, to be able to deploy it, so it can be accessed by other researchers, developers and applications.
A very common way to accomplish that is by using an API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Post</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/instruction/00samplepost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/research/instruction/00samplepost/</guid>
      <description>TEST #hugo
import numpy as np import pandas as pd 2+3  A Gentle Introduction to Neural Network Fundamentals 
Imagine the following problem: There are handwritten numbers that you want computer to correctly clasify. It would be an easy task for a person but an extremely complicated one for a machine, especially, if you want to use some traditional prediction model, like linear regression. Even though the computer is faster than the human brain in numeric computations, the brain far outperforms the computer in some tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the Contributors</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Prof. Dr. Stefan Lessmann Prof. Lessmann is the head of the chair Information Systems at the Humboldt University of Berlin. In cooperation with his team, he initiated this website in oder to present, inform and discuss latest research results. For his more extensive bio click here. In research, he is most active in:
 Artificial neural networks, deep learning Big Data Analytics Credit risk modeling Ensemble models and forecast combination Marketing and E-Commerce analytics Non-standard paradigms to learn from data Sentiment and social network analysis Time series forecasting</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://humboldt-wi.github.io/blog/contact/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to get in touch with you. For directly contacting us, please use one of the following:  Contact Person: Anna-Lena Bujarek
Room: 326
Telephone: +49 30 2093-5742
Fax:+49 30 2093-5741
E-mail: bujarek@hu-berlin.de
  
If you prefer mailing, see our address here: Humboldt-University of Berlin School of Business and Economics Chair of Information Systems University: Unter den Linden 6, 10099 Berlin Faculty: Spandauer Straße 1, 10178 Berlin</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>